In this video, we're gonna talk a little bit about concurrency in programming
在这段视频中，我们将稍微讨论一下编程中的并发性
languages and in particular, Java's use of threads. Java has concurrency built in
语言，特别是Java对线程的使用。Java具有内置的并发性
through threads and I'm not going to explain what a thread is from first
通过线程，我不会先解释线程是什么
principles in this video. So I'm going to assume a little bit of background but
这段视频中的原则。所以我要假设一点背景，但是
we'll say a few words here about what threads are. So a thread is like its own
在这里，我们将简单介绍一下线程是什么。所以一条线就像它自己的线一样
program. It has its own program counter, meaning, it has an instruction that it's
程序。它有自己的程序计数器，也就是说，它有一条指令
executing and it has its own set of local variables and activation records. And a
执行，并且它有自己的一组局部变量和激活记录。和一个
Java program, or any program written in any language with threads may have
Java程序或用任何语言编写的任何带有线程的程序都可能具有
multiple threads at the same time. So, abstractly, we can think of threads as
同时使用多个线程。因此，抽象地说，我们可以将线程视为
being a series of exec, of, of statements that are executed. Each, one of these
是被执行的语句的一系列EXEC、OF、OF。每一个，这些中的一个
threads again, has its own set of local variables. But the threads may refer to
线程也有自己的一组局部变量。但是这些线程可能会引用
common data in the heap. So they could refer to the same heap data structures.
堆中的公共数据。因此它们可以引用相同的堆数据结构。
And, each thread is executing a particular instruction, so let's say that the threads
而且，每个线程都在执行一条特定的指令，所以让我们假设这些线程
are all, here we have three threads, one, two, and three. And they're each at some
都齐了，这里有三条线，一条、二条和三条。他们每个人都在某种程度上
instruction or some, statement in the program. And then there is a scheduler and
程序中的指令或某些语句。然后有一个调度器，
at each step of execution, the scheduler will pick one thread to execute. And it'll
在执行的每个步骤中，调度程序都会选择一个线程来执行。然后它就会
execute one statement. And this is conceptual. Meaning, this isn't exactly
执行一条语句。这是概念性的。意思是，这并不完全是
the way it's usually implemented. And then it will repeat this loop. So it'll pick a
它通常的实现方式。然后它会重复这个循环。所以它会选择一个
thread, it'll execute one statement of that thread and it'll just keep doing that
线程，它会执行该线程的一条语句，并且会一直这样做
over and over again. So we might for example, the schedule might pick thread
一遍又一遍。因此我们可能，例如，日程安排可能会选择线程
one and execute this first statement. And then it might pick thread two and execute
1并执行这第一条语句。然后它可能会选择线程2并执行
this statement, and then it might pick thread three and execute that statement.
该语句，然后它可能选择线程3并执行该语句。
And then it might decide well to execute another statement of thread two, and then
然后它可能会很好地决定执行线程2的另一条语句，然后
it might execute several statements of thread one. And then it might come back
它可能执行线程1的几个语句。然后它可能会回来
and execute a couple statements of thread three, and then thread two might get to go
并执行线程3的几个语句，然后线程2可能开始
again for a while, and so on. All right, so, the threads execute in some order. And
再来一段时间，以此类推。好的，所以，线程按一定的顺序执行。和
it's non-deterministic at each step of execution which thread will execute, how
它在执行的每一步都是不确定的，哪个线程将执行，如何执行
many of its instructions will be executed. And, and thus the threads may inter-lead,
它的许多指令将被执行。并且因此线程可以相互引导，
the instructions in the threads may inter-lead in a relatively or, in fact,
线程中的指令可以在相对或事实上，
completely arbitrary order. Alright? Now, coming back to how this is done in Java,
完全武断的顺序。好吗？现在，回到Java是如何做到这一点的，
thread objects in Java all have class threads. So there's a special class that
Java中的Thread对象都有类线程。所以有一个特殊的班级
you have to inherit from in order to be a thread. And what you get, when you inherit
你必须继承才能成为一条线。当你继承的时候，你会得到什么
from the thread class is, you will have start and stop methods for beginning and
在Thread类中，您将拥有开始和停止的Start和Stop方法
ending the thread. Alright? And there's some other special properties of threads.
结束线程。好吗？还有一些线程的其他特殊性质。
And in particular, one thing that threads can do is to synchronize on objects. So,
特别值得一提的是，线程可以做的一件事就是在对象上使用同步。所以,
a, a, a thread can, acquire a lock on an object through the synchronized construct.
线程可以通过同步构造获得对象上的锁。
And so if I say synchronized xe in Java, what that means is, that the program will
因此，如果我在Java中说同步Xe，这意味着程序将
acquire a lock on x before it executes e. So the procedure here will be to lock x,
在x执行e之前获取它的锁。所以这里的过程将是锁定x，
then evaluate e, and then unlock x, alright? So it's a structured
然后计算e，然后解锁x，好吗？所以这是一个结构化的
synchronization construct. And within, while it is executing the expression e, it
同步构造。在内部，当它执行表达式e时，它
will hold a lock on x. And this is the primary way, really almost the only way in
将锁定x。这是主要的途径，几乎是唯一进入的途径
Java, to get synchronization between, multiple threads. So this is how we, one
Java，以获得多个线程之间的同步。所以这就是我们，一个
can control the set of interleavings because while one thread is executing,
可以控制交织集合，因为当一个线程正在执行时，
this particular block of code, no other thread can execute this block of code and
这种特殊的挡路代码，没有其他线程可以执行这种挡路代码
also hold a lock on the same object x. Now could, two threads could execute this same
还可以在同一对象x上持有锁。现在可以，两个线程可以执行相同的操作
syntactic construct if they were locking, if, if their local variables actually
语法构造，如果它们是锁定的，如果，如果它们的局部变量实际上
referred to different objects. But they're guaranteed not to interfere with each
指的是不同的对象。但他们保证不会干扰每一个人
other, not to interweave, if they tried to lock the same object x, alright? Now
其他的，不是交织的，如果他们试图锁定相同的物体x，好吗？现在
there's one shorthand in Java which is used more commonly than this form, the
在Java中有一种速记，它比这种形式更常用，那就是
synchronized construct. And as the synchronization can be put on methods. We
同步构造。并且由于同步可以放在方法上。我们
can say, synchronized f, where this is a method definition. Alright? An d what this
可以说是同步的f，其中这是一个方法定义。好吗？这是什么？
means is that, when this method is called, that this object will be locked. So here,
意味着当调用此方法时，此对象将被锁定。所以在这里，
the object that's going to be locked is implicit. And when synchronized is
要锁定的对象是隐式的。而当同步时，
attached to a method name, or a method declaration, that always means that this
附加到方法名称或方法声明，这始终意味着这
parameter will be the synchronized or locked object. Let's take a look at the
参数将是同步或锁定的对象。我们来看一下
simple example and think about what happens if we have two methods, one of
简单的示例，并考虑如果我们有两个方法，其中一个是
which calls the method two of the class simple and one of which calls the method
它调用方法两个类Simple，其中一个调用该方法
fro. So let's take a look at that, let's say we have thread one and thread two. And
前排。让我们来看看这一点，假设我们有线程1和线程2。和
now, thread one is going to invoke the method two and thread two is going to
现在，线程1将调用方法2，线程2将调用
invoke the method fro. All right? So one possibility here, let's say that, that two
调用的方法。好的?所以这里有一种可能性，比方说，那两个
gets to run all the way to completion before fro executes anything. So then
在fro执行任何操作之前一直运行到完成。那么，那么
we'll have a = three and b = four, okay? And then fro will run and it will print
我们会有a=3和b=4，好吗？然后，fro将运行并打印
out the string a = three, b = four. Okay? So that's a relatively simple straight
出字符串a=3，b=4。好吧?所以这是一条相对简单的直线
forward case. You know another possibility is that thread two gets to run before
前述案例。你知道另一种可能性是线程2在运行之前
thread one ever does anything. So thread two executes all of it's instructions
线上的人曾经做过任何事。所以线程2执行它的所有指令
before thread one executes anything at all. In which case what will be printed.
在线程1执行任何东西之前。在这种情况下，将打印什么。
Well, the fro will print out a = one, b = two, alright? And two will then run, and
嗯，FRO会打印出a=1，b=2，好吗？然后两个人会跑起来，然后
it will set after this executes. So, after this, after fro finishes executing, it
它将在此执行后设置。所以在这之后，在fro执行完之后，它
will then set a = three and b = four. That's another possibility and both of
然后设置a=3和b=4。这是另一种可能性，而且
those are fine, alright? But then there are some other odd possibilities, and
这些都很好，好吗？但是还有其他一些奇怪的可能性，而且
let's take a look at one of those. What happens if the thread is actually enter
让我们来看看其中的一个。如果线程实际进入会发生什么情况
leave in a non-trivial way. So let's consider the following possibilities.
以一种不平凡的方式离开。因此，让我们考虑以下可能性。
Let's say that two executes these assignment, a = three. And now fro
假设两个人执行这些赋值，a=3。现在是前前后后
executes the first part of the print. So, it does the read of a and starts building
执行打印的第一部分。因此，它读取a并开始构建
up this output string, okay? So, it's going to print out here, a = three,
把这个输出字符串向上，好吗？所以，它将打印在这里，a=3，
alright? And then, now lets say that fro actually goes ahead and gets to run some
好吗？然后，现在让我们假设fro实际上运行了一些
more and also goes ahead and prints out the rest of this. Okay? So, actually does
更多的，还在继续打印出这个的睡觉。好吧?所以，实际上是这样的
the second read of b so the n it will print b = two. All right? And then one
第二次读取b，所以n将打印b=2。好的?然后再来一个
will run, the rest of the way through, excuse me, b = four. And so here we got an
要跑的话，睡觉一路过去，打扰一下，b=4。所以我们这里有一个
output that doesn't seem quite right. Here we got, we were able to see an
产出看起来不太对劲。在这里，我们可以看到一个
intermediate state where thread one had only executed partially. And so, what came
线程1仅部分执行的中间状态。那么，后来发生了什么呢？
out over here, in fro show you know, just a partial update of the variables a and b.
在这里，在fro show中，只更新了变量a和b的一部分。
So one had been written but not the other. And if we didn't want to do that, if we
所以一个已经写好了，而另一个没有。如果我们不想这么做，如果我们
thought this was wrong, we would have to use synchronization in order to control
虽然这是错误的，但我们将不得不使用同步来控制
that. So, let's take a look then at using synchronization to try to prevent this
那。那么，让我们看一下如何使用同步来尝试防止这种情况
from happening. And I'll tell you right upfront that this piece of code or this
避免发生。我要直截了当地告诉你，这段代码或者这段
attempt is incorrect and actually it doesn't solve the problem at all. But it
尝试是不正确的，实际上根本解决不了问题。但是它
also illustrates probably the most common thread programming error that Java
还说明了Java可能最常见的线程编程错误
programmers make. And lots of people, including professional programmers make
程序员制造。很多人，包括专业程序员
this mistake and lots of production Java programs have this particular mistake in
这个错误和许多生产Java程序在
them. So it's a very instructive example, I think. So let's take a look here. Let's
他们。所以我认为这是一个非常有启发性的例子。那么让我们来看看这里。我们走吧
assume we have the, the two threads again. The thread is going to call two and the
假设我们又有了，这两条线。线程将调用Two，而
thread is going to call fro. And let's say that, in our heap, there is only one
线程将调用FRO。假设在我们的堆中只有一个
object simple, and let's just call it s. So this is globally, in the entire heap
对象简单，我们就称它为s。所以这是全局的，在整个堆中
just one object, s, of the simple class. Alright? So what is, let's say that thread
只有一个简单类的对象%s。好吗？那么，让我们假设这条线索
one is going to go first, alright, and the first that it's going to do, because it's,
一个要先走，好的，第一个要做的，因为它是，
synchronized method, is it's going to lock the this parameter of the call since
同步方法，它是否会锁定调用的this参数，因为
there's only one simple, only one, object of the simple class that has to be the
简单类中只有一个简单的、只有一个对象必须是
object s, so it's going to lock s. Alright, now we'll prevent any other
对象%s，所以它将锁定%s。好的，现在我们将阻止任何其他
thread from acquiring the lock on s while, while thread one holds that lock. So then,
线程1持有该锁时，线程不能获取%s While上的锁。那么，那么，
thread one can go ahead and execute the statement a = three. And now though, we
线程1可以继续执行语句a=3。但现在，我们
could have interruption and thread two can get to run. And notice here that thread
可能会有中断，线程2可以开始运行。注意这根线
two doesn't check the lock. It goes ahead execute this code over here. In the f ro
二号不能检查锁。它继续在这里执行这段代码。在f中
method but that's not synchronized, there is no synchronize keyword there. And so
方法，但这不是同步的，那里没有同步关键字。因此，
just the fact that somebody else holds the lock on a simple object doesn't prevent
仅仅是其他人持有简单对象的锁这一事实并不能阻止
another method from accessing the fields or the data of that object if that other
访问该对象的字段或数据的另一种方法，如果另一种
method doesn't itself check the lock. So if the other method is not synchronized,
方法本身不检查锁。因此，如果另一种方法不同步，
it will just go ahead and, and, and, and execute ignoring the fact that another
它将继续并执行，而忽略另一个事实
thread holds the lock on the object. So, in this case, this will just, this can
线程持有对象上的锁。所以，在这种情况下，这个就是，这个可以
just run to completion. And we'll print out, a = three, b = two. Okay? So we only
只要完成就行了。我们会打印出来，a=3，b=2。好吧?所以我们只有
see one of the two updates. And, and then the scheduler can come back in. Let's the
请参阅两个更新之一。然后，然后调度员就可以回来了。让我们一起来
other thread run and it would run to completion and unlock the object at the
其他线程运行，它将运行到完成，并在
end. And you could see here that this particular attempted fix has achieved
结束。你可以在这里看到，这种特殊的尝试修复已经实现了
nothing. Actually all the possible inter leavings of the two methods that were,
没什么。实际上，这两种方法的所有可能的交错，
that existed without any synchronization still exist if only one of the two methods
如果这两种方法中只有一种方法存在，则在没有任何同步的情况下仍然存在
is synchronized. And the reason this error is common is because frequently people
是同步的。这个错误之所以常见，是因为人们经常
think well, I, you know if reads are okay I can always read from things in parallel
好好想一想，我，你知道，如果阅读可以的话，我总是可以并行阅读的
and that won't cause any problems because I'm not altering any data. It's my writes
这不会造成任何问题，因为我没有更改任何数据。这是我写的
that have to be synchronized, so if I'm going to write to fields of objects well
它们必须是同步的，所以如果我要很好地写入对象的字段
that needs to be coordinated with other methods because writes are dangerous but
这需要与其他方法协调，因为写入是危险的，但是
reads somehow don't interfere. And the point here is that if, having only one
阅读不知何故不会干扰你。这里的重点是，如果只有一个
method, or only having one half of the accesses to the, of two accesses to shared
方法，或者对共享的两个访问中只有一半的访问。
data be synchronized doesn't help because synchronization only works if everybody is
要同步的数据没有帮助，因为只有当每个人都同步时，同步才会起作用
checking the lock. So both the reader and the writer need to check the lock in order
正在检查锁。因此读取器和写入器都需要按顺序检查锁
to restrict the set of possible interleavings of these two methods. So,
以限制这两种方法的可能交织的集合。所以,
what would be a correct way to do it? Well, is just to put the synchronized
做这件事的正确方法是什么？嗯，就是把同步的
keyword on both methods. And now. It's not possible to have the interleaving we saw
两种方法上的关键字。现在呢。我们看到的交错是不可能的
before it's not just only two possible outputs. One, there are only two possible
在此之前，它不仅仅是两种可能的输出。第一，只有两种可能
strings that could be p rinted. One is that a = one and b = two. So, in this
可以打印的字符串。一个是a=1，b=2。所以，在这件事上
case, the fro method executes before the two method, so that's fro before two,
在这种情况下，fro方法在两个方法之前执行，所以在两个方法之前是fro，
okay? I mean, all of fro before all of the two method. And the other possibility is a
好吧?我是说，在这两种方法之前都是这样。另一种可能性是
= three, b = four, alright? And that would be the two method executing in its
=三，b=四，好吗？这将是在其
entirety before the fro method. And those become the only two possible
在fro方法之前是整体。这就成了仅有的两种可能
inter-leavings when both methods here are synchronized. I'm going to conclude this
此处的两个方法同步时的交错。我要得出这样的结论
video by making a couple of other comments on Java's threads. So, one property we
通过在Java的线程上做一些其他的评论来播放视频。所以，我们有一处房产
would like, is that even if there is no synchronization, a variable should only
我想说的是，即使没有同步，变量也应该只
hold values that were actually written by some threads. So, what do I mean by that?
保存某些线程实际写入的值。那么，我这么说是什么意思呢？
Let's say that we have two assignments. This is in thread one, where we're
假设我们有两个作业。这是线程一，我们在这里
assigning a the value of 3.14, then in thread two, we're assigning a the value
赋值为3.14，然后在线程2中，我们为赋值
2.78. And so after these assignments are done, after they've executed in some
2.78。所以在这些任务完成之后，在他们执行了一些
order, what do we expect? Well, we expect that a ends up being equal either to 3.14
秩序，我们还能期待什么？我们预计a最终会等于3.14
or 2.78, alright? Now what we don't want is for a to wind up being some other
或者2.78，好吗？现在我们不想看到的是一个人最终变成了另一个人
value, okay? I mean what if a turned out to be 3.78 for example, okay? This would
价值，好吗？我的意思是，如果a结果是3.78怎么办，好吗？这将会
be bad, we don't want this, right? Because this value, 3.78, was never written by
做坏人，我们不想这样，对吧？因为这个值3.78从来不是由
either thread. Okay, this value was somehow manufactured. And I've chose 3.78,
任一条线都行。好的，这个值是以某种方式制造出来的。我选择了3.78，
to kind of indicate what could potentially go wrong. If we somehow wound up with a
某种程度上表明可能会出什么问题。如果我们以某种方式以一种
mix of the bits or the, the pieces of the number from thread one and thread two. If
把线一和线二的数字碎片混合在一起。如果
they were re-combined in some strange way, then we could create a number, that was
它们以某种奇怪的方式重新组合，然后我们就可以创造一个数字，那就是
assigned to a that didn't exist in either thread. Okay, it was never actually
分配给在两个线程中都不存在的。好吧，实际上从来都不是
written in either thread. Now, Java does guarantee that the rights of values are
写在任一线程中。现在，Java确实保证了值的权利是
atomic. Meaning that if I write to a value, if I sign a primitive type to
原子弹。这意味着如果我写入值，如果我给基元类型签名
something, that is going to happen atomically and won't be interfered with by
一些事情，它将自动发生，不会被
another assignment to the same memory location except for floating point
对同一内存位置(浮点除外)的另一赋值
doubles. So this does not hold writes to doubles or not necessarily atomic. Now,
双人间。因此，这不包含对Double的写入，也不一定是原子写入。现在,
why would that be? Well, a double is a floating point number, but it consumes
为什么会这样呢？嗯，双精度数是一个浮点数，但是它消耗
twice the memory. That's why it's called a double, it consumes two words. Okay, and
是记忆的两倍。这就是为什么它被称为双字，它消耗两个单词。好的，还有
what that means is that if a here is a double, so let's assume that a is a
这意味着，如果这里的a是双精度的，那么让我们假设a是一个
double. That means that this write of 3.14 actually translates into two machine
双倍。这意味着3.14写入实际上转换为两台机器
instructions. We have to write the high part of a equals something and then the
说明书。我们必须写出a的高位部分等于某个值，然后
lower part of a. So, the two machine instructions to write both of the words
a的下半部分。所以，两个机器指令来写这两个词
that represent a after writing the high half and the low half. Okay because there
这表示在写完上半部分和下半部分之后。好的，因为在那里
isn't a, a primitive double word write on most machines. And the same thing would
不是大多数机器上原始的双字书写。同样的事情也会发生
happen in thread two. This would get broken up into two assignments to the two
发生在线程2中。这将被分解成两个分配给两个人的任务
halves of a. And then, just from what we discussed before, you can see that these
然后，从我们之前讨论的内容可以看出，这些
could interleave in some way and you might wind up with the unfortunate situation
可能会以某种方式交织在一起，最终你可能会陷入不幸的境地
that the high half of the representation of a is written by thread one, and the low
A表示的上半部分由线程1写入，而下半部分由线程1写入
half is written by thread two, and then you can get a number like this, like you
一半是由线程2写的，然后你可以得到一个像这样的数字，就像你一样
know, something not exactly 3.78, but some mix of the bits from the write in thread
确切地说，不是3.78，而是写入线程中的一些位的混合
one and the write at thread two, and you would create what's called an out of thin
线程1和线程2处的写入，您将创建所谓的超薄
air value. Okay, and clearly out of thin air values are bad. Okay, you do not want
空气值。好吧，很明显，无中生有的价值观是不好的。好的，你不会想要
those. And, and Java guarantees, again, that the rights of almost all the
那些。而且，Java再次保证，几乎所有
primitive data types are going to be atomic so you can't get out of thin air
原始数据类型将是原子的，因此您不能凭空获得
values. But for performance reasons, this is not the case for doubles. All right.
价值。但出于性能原因，双打情况并非如此。好的。
So, so, so, for fro as a, what it says in the manual is that as a concession, the
所以，作为一个，手册上说的是，作为一种让步，
current hardware, they do not require that rights to doubles be atomic unless you the
当前的硬件，它们不需要双精度的权限是原子的，除非您的
programmer go and mark the type as volatile. So you have to declare doubles
程序员前往并将该类型标记为易失性。所以你必须申报双人
to be volatile, and if you do that, then they're guaranteed to be atomic writes.
易失性，如果这样做，那么它们肯定是原子写入。
Okay, so if you were writing Java programs using Java threads, and you were
好的，如果您正在使用Java线程编写Java程序，并且您
programming threads that read and write doubles concurrently, then you need to be
编程并发读取和写入双倍数据的线程，那么您需要
careful to declare those double types volatil e, at least currently, and this
至少在当前，要小心地声明这两种类型，并且这
may change in the future, and I'm sure they'd like to change it. But currently
未来可能会改变，我相信他们也想改变。但目前
you have to declare the doubles volatile to guarantee that the writes will be
您必须声明DOUBLE是易失性的，以保证写入将是
atomic. More generally, or actually somewhat separately, this is actually a
原子弹。更笼统地说，或者实际上有些不同，这实际上是一个
separate point here, Java concurrency semantics are actually kind of hard to
另外一点，Java并发语义实际上很难
understand in detail. And this, this issue around, out of thin air values, is, is one
详细了解。而这个，这个围绕着的这个问题，凭空而来的价值，就是，
aspect of this. There are several other aspects, of it. And, and, and this is
这件事的一个方面。它还有其他几个方面。还有，还有，这是
really not Java's fault. It turns out the concurrency semantics are hard and
真的不是Java的错。事实证明，并发语义很难实现，而且
actually, this is kind of at the frontier of research. We don't really understand
实际上，这是一种研究的前沿。我们不太明白
exactly what we want or what the right thing is to do, to specify the behavior of
确切地说我们想要什么，或者什么是正确的事情要做，来具体说明
languages, in concurrent settings. And, that's not to say that we don't understand
语言，在并发设置中。而且，这并不是说我们不理解
anything. We do have some languages in perfectly, concurrency semantics but in a
什么都行。我们确实有一些语言在完美的并发语义中，但是在
language, flow in language, feature is Java, there are a number of things that
语言，在语言中流动，功能是Java，有很多东西
are not completely clear how they should be implemented on certain machines. So
并不完全清楚它们应该如何在某些机器上实现。所以
this has been a huge amount of work done on this problems specifically for Java and
这是专门针对Java和Java在这个问题上所做的大量工作
actually java was the first mainstream language to have first class threads in it
实际上，java是第一种拥有一级线程的主流语言。
and then try to integrate that with all other language features that all other
然后尝试将其与所有其他语言功能集成
modern languages features that we like. It was so surprising actually that we have
现代语言是我们喜欢的特色。事实上，我们有这么多令人惊讶的
run into some trouble understanding how they are supposed to work in all
在理解他们应该如何工作时遇到了一些麻烦
situations. So this is one area of Java that I would say still under debate. And
情况。所以这是Java的一个领域，我想说它仍然在争论中。和
while for them, while I figure out straight forward things with threads
而对他们来说，当我用线程直接解决问题时
everything will work fine. If you are doing, there are some areas of the
一切都会很好的。如果您正在执行此操作，则
language where if you try to use them with threads, you can get into a little bit of
这是一种语言，如果您尝试将它们与线程一起使用，您可以了解一些
trouble. Alright, so it surely pays to try to understand. Java concurrency and the
麻烦。好的，所以试着去理解当然是值得的。Java并发性和
threads if you're writing significant concurrency Java programs
线程(如果您正在编写重要的并发Java程序